A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications (Non-Grant Related), Accession 2017:050 FA1304
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Publications, 1
  - Prints and Printmaking - Plates - Series B, undated (Box 86, Folder 1016)
    Plates accompanying Prints and Printmaking
  - Modern Fiction: Form and Idea in the Contemporary Novel & Short Story, Deborah S. Austin, Ralph W. Condee, and Chadwick C. Hansen, Center for Continuing Liberal Education, The Pennsylvania State University, 1959 (Box 86, Folder 1017)
  - Problems of International Understanding and World Affairs - First Edition - Unit One-Unit 5, Elton Atwater, William Butz, Kent Forster, and Neal Riemer, The Pennsylvania State University, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 1018-1019)
    Introduction by Milton S. Eisenhower, Unit One: The Individual and the Contemporary Crisis in World Affairs, Unit Two: Unity and Diversity in World Affairs, Unit Three: Contemporary Ideologies in World Affairs, Unit Four: Techniques of Adjustment in World Affairs, Unit Five: Practicum in World Affairs
  - Exploring Religious Ideas: The Great Western Faiths, Benjamin M. Kahn, Luther Harshbarger, John A. Mourant, Ralph W. Condee, Center for Continuing Liberal Education, The Pennsylvania State University, 1959 (Box 86, Folder 1020)
  - Attending the Theatre: Enjoying Contemporary Drama, Walter H. Walters, Warren Smith, Edwin W. Zoller, Center for Continuing Liberal Education, The Pennsylvania State University, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1021)
  - Leading Study-Discussion Programs: A Guide for Trainers and Participants, Center for Continuing Liberal Education, The Pennsylvania State University, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1022)
  - Everyone His Own Historian: A Guide for Studying the History Around You, Wallace F. Workmaster and Robert W. Iversen, Center for Continuing Liberal Education, The Pennsylvania State University, 1960 (Box 87, Folder 1023)
  - Pennsylvania State University Communications Forum #1, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1024)
    Contents include: Books on the Responsibility of the Press and Broadcasting and Selected Articles on Press Responsibility and Problems
  - The Wheat Situation in the United States: A Statement of Policy by the Kansas City Committee for Economic Development (CED) Associates Center, Kansas City, Missouri, 1962 April (Box 87, Folder 1025)
  - Economic Education in the San Francisco Bay Area: A Policy Statement by the Bay Area Committee for Economic Development (CED) Associates Center, 1963 January (Box 87, Folder 1026)
  - Three Aspects of Industrial Development in Georgia: A Statement of Policy by Atlanta Committee for Economic Development (CED) Associates Center, Atlanta, Georgia, 1963 January (Box 87, Folder 1027)
    Three Aspects of Industrial Development in Georgia - Full Development of Human Abilities, The Role of Finance in Industrial Development, and Coordination of Industrial Development Efforts
  - Economic Base Report 9 - Projections of Greater Boston's Population to 1970 and 1980, Frank L. Sweetser, Boston University, Greater Boston Economic Study Committee, Associate Center of the Committee for Economic Development, 1962 July (Box 87, Folder 1028)
  - Adult Education: A Directory of National Organizations Represented in the Council of National Organizations of the Adult Education Association, 1954 (Box 87, Folder 1029)
  - How to Make Your Savings Work for You - Part I, Business Executives' Research Committee (BERC), A Joint Research Project Under the Auspices of the School of Business Administration, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1952 May (Box 87, Folder 1030)
  - What People Are Doing With Their Savings Now, A Pilot Study of 200 Individual Cases - Part II of a Study on Savings, Business Executives' Research Committee (BERC), A Joint Research Project Under the Auspices of the School of Business Administration, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1952 August (Box 87, Folder 1031)
  - Businessmen in Government: An Appraisal of Experience, Harvard Business School Club of Washington, D.C., 1958 May (Box 87, Folder 1032)
  - Trade Negotiations for a Better Free World Economy: A Statement on National Policy by the Research and Policy Committee of the Committee for Economic Development, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 1033)
  - National Defense and Southern California 1961-1970, Southern California Associates of the Committee for Economic Development Together With a Research Report by George A. Steiner, 1961 December (Box 88, Folder 1034)
  - Alabama's Manufacturing Economy: A Report by Alabama Business Research Council and School of Commerce and Business Administration, University of Alabama, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 1035)
  - Planning for Capital Expenditures in Private Enterprise, Business Executives' Research Committee (BERC), 1954 January (Box 88, Folder 1036)
  - Sources of Capital for New Manufacturing Firms in Oklahoma, Business Advisory Council, The University of Oklahoma, and Business Executives' Research Committee (BERC), 1955 (Box 88, Folder 1037)
  - Corporate Giving in Greater Cleveland: A Survey by the Harvard Business School Club of Cleveland, Inc., 1953 December (Box 88, Folder 1038)
  - Manufacturing Potential in the Pacific Northwest: An Occasional Paper of the Bureau of Business Research, College of Business Administration, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, 1959 December (Box 88, Folder 1039)
    Occasional Paper Number 10
  - The Impact of World War II Subcontracting by the Boeing Airplane Company upon Pacific Northwest Manufacturing, Business Executives' Advisory Board, University of Washington, and Business Executives' Research Committee, undated (Box 88, Folder 1040)
  - Energy Base of the Pacific Northwest Economy: A Regional Analysis of Supply, Utilization, and Cost of Energy, A Research Project Co-Sponsored by Pacific Northwest Trade Association and Bureau of Business Research, University of Washington, Endel J. Kolde, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 1041)
  - Land Use Report 1 - Land Use in Greater Boston in 1960, Greater Boston Economic Study Committee, Associate Center of the Committee of Economic Development, 1962 May (Box 88, Folder 1042)
    - Greater Boston Oversize Map, 1960; 2017:050:003 (Box Separated, Item 2017:050:003)
      Separated Materials
      Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Land Use Report 2 - Industrial Land Needs Through 1980, Greater Boston Economic Study Committee, Associate Center of the Committee for Economic Development, Melvin R. Levin and David A. Grossman, The Planning Services Group, 1962 May (Box 88, Folder 1043)
  - Economic Base Report 10 - The Electronics Industry of Greater Boston, Everett J. Burtt, Jr., Greater Boston Economic Study Committee, Associate Center of the Committee for Economic Development, 1962 July (Box 88, Folder 1044)
  - The Forest Products Industry of Oregon - Part 1. A Report of the Business Executives' Research Committee Sponsored by the Lewis and Clark College and Reed College, Portland, Oregon, 1954 December (Box 88, Folder 1045)
  - Ford Foundation Report Summer 1994 - Taming Troubled Waters: Finally, A New Course for Montana's Clark Fork River, Vol. 25, No. 2 (2 copies) (Box 88, Folder 1046)
  - Ford Foundation Report Fall 1994 - Special Report: Mexico, Beyond the Balance of Trade, Vol. 25, No. 3 (2 copies) (Box 89, Folder 1047)
  - Ford Foundation Report Winter 1995 - Pacific Northwest: Creating Jobs that Sustain the Economy, Vol. 26, No. 1 (2 copies) (Box 89, Folder 1048)
  - Ford Foundation Report Spring 1995 - Palestinian Women and the Law: Seeking an Equal Share, Vol. 26, No. 2 (2 copies) (Box 89, Folder 1049)
  - Ford Foundation Report Winter 1998 - Down Payment on the American Dream: Given the Chance, Poor People Will Save for a Stake in Society, Vol. 29, No. 1 (Box 89, Folder 1050)
  - Ford Foundation Report Winter 1999 - The Arts Mean Business, Vol. 30, No. 1 (Box 89, Folder 1051)
  - Three Decades of Progress: Step by Step, The Global Community of Women Pull-Out Poster (2 copies), 2000; 2017:050:006 (Box Separated, Item 2017:050:006)
    Special format items have been separated from the above listed file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Ford Foundation Report Summer 2000 - Reimagining the Past: El Warsha Theater Challenges Cultural Orthodoxy in Egypt, Vol. 31, No. 3 (2 copies) (Box 89, Folder 1052)
  - The Challenge of Local Feminisms: Women's Movements in Global Perspective, Amrita Basu (2 copies), 1995 (Box 89, Folder 1053-1054)
  - International Urbanization Survey: Findings and Recommendations (2 copies), undated (Box 90, Folder 1055)
    Contents: Document 1: Statement of Findings, Document 2: Supporting and Explanatory Discussion, Document 3: The Ford Foundation Experience, Document 4: The Foundation's Options, Document 5: Operational Proposals to the Ford Foundation, Appendix: Working Papers, and Country Surveys: Jamaica, Brazil, Colombia, Venezuela, Peru, Chile, Tropical Africa, Nigeria, Kenya, Zambia, Morocco, Turkey, India, and Thailand
  - Urbanization in Turkey: An International Urbanization Survey, The Ford Foundation, Rusen Keles, Ankara University, Turkey, 1971 (Box 90, Folder 1056)
  - Urbanization in Argentina: International Urbanization Survey, The Ford Foundation and Correspondence, 1991 (Box 90, Folder 1057)
    Correspondence from 1991, Urbanization in Argentina is undated
  - Urbanization in Pakistan: International Urbanization Survey, The Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 90, Folder 1058)
  - The Great Society: Lessons for the Future, Eli Ginzberg and Robert M. Solow (2 copies), 1974 (Box 90, Folder 1059)
  - Program Index to Ford Foundation Letter, 1970-1981 (Box 91, Folder 1060)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 1, No. 1-6, 1970 (Box 91, Folder 1061)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 2, No. 1-8, 1971 (Box 91, Folder 1062)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 3, No. 1-8, 1972 (Box 91, Folder 1063)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 4, No. 1-8, 1973 (Box 91, Folder 1064)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 5, No. 1-8, 1974 (Box 91, Folder 1065)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 6, No.1-7, 1975 (Box 91, Folder 1066)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 7, No. 1-6, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 1067)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 8, No.1-6, 1977 (Box 91, Folder 1068)
    No. 3 misprinted as Vol. 9
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 9, No. 1-6, 1978 (Box 91, Folder 1069)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 10, No. 1-6, 1979 (Box 91, Folder 1070)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 11, No. 1-6, 1980 (Box 91, Folder 1071)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 12, No. 1-6, 1981 (Box 91, Folder 1072)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 13, No. 1-6, 1982 (Box 91, Folder 1073)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 14, No. 1-6, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 1074)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 15, No. 1-6, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 1075)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 16, No. 2, 4-6, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 1076)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 17, No. 1, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 1077)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 18, No. 1-6, 1987 (Box 91, Folder 1078)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 19, No. 1-4, 1988 (Box 91, Folder 1079)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 21, No. 2, 1990 (Box 91, Folder 1080)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 22, No. 1-3, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 1081)
    No. 1 - 2 copies
  - Ford Foundation Report Fall 1992 - Fathers and Families: Forging Ties that Bind, Vol. 23, No. 3 (3 copies) (Box 92, Folder 1082)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 20, No. 1, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 1083)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, Vol. 21, No. 1, 1990 (Box 92, Folder 1084)
  - Ford Foundation Report Winter 1992 - Combating Poverty in Rural China: Change Comes to Anwing, China, Vol. 23, No. 4 (2 copies) (Box 92, Folder 1085)
  - Ford Foundation Report Spring 1993 - San Antonio's Latino Artists, Young and Old, Vol. 24, No. 1 (2 copies) (Box 92, Folder 1086)
  - Ford Foundation Report Summer 1993 - Quasar: Math with a Twist, Vol. 24, No. 2 (Box 92, Folder 1087)
  - Ford Foundation Report Fall 1993 - Women Unite to Change South Africa, Vol. 24, No. 3 (2 copies) (Box 92, Folder 1088)
  - Ford Foundation Report Winter 1993 - Our Village, Our Family, Our Lives: Peasant Women Portray a New View of Rural China, Vol. 24, No. 4 (2 copies) (Box 92, Folder 1089)
  - Field Office Administrative Procedures - Ford Foundation New Delhi Administrative Procedures Manual, 1998 April (Box 92, Folder 1090)
  - Field Office Administrative Procedures - Brazil Field Office, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, Administrative Procedures Manual, 1998 September (Box 92, Folder 1091)
  - Field Office Administrative Procedures - Administrative Procedure Manual, Andean Region and Southern Cone, Santiago Field Office, Chile, 1996 February (Box 92, Folder 1092)
  - Field Office Administrative Procedures - Dakar, Senegal, Office Procedures Manual, 1996 February (Box 92, Folder 1093)
  - Field Office Administrative Procedures - The Ford Foundation Office for Eastern and Southern Africa, Harare Office Procedures Manual, 1995 June (Box 92, Folder 1094)
  - International Human Rights Training for Indigenous Peoples: A Review, Analysis, and Inventory of Programs, 2002 May (Box 92, Folder 1095)
  - Advancing Sexual and Reproductive Health in Academic and Research Institutions in the Middle East North Africa Region: Summary of Lessons Learned from Grants Made by the Ford Foundation Cairo Office, 2009 September (Box 92, Folder 1096)
  - Letting Flowers Bloom: The Growth of Reproductive Health Efforts in Egypt: Lessons Learned from Pre- and Post-International Conference on Population and Development (ICPD) Grants Made By The Ford Foundation Cairo Office, 2009 September (Box 92, Folder 1097)
  - The Ford Foundation India and Nepal: Bibliography of Substantive Writings, Third Edition, New Delhi, 1969 April 1 (Box 92, Folder 1098)
  - Bibliography of Substantive Writings: Supplement to the Third Edition, New Delhi, 1970 September 1 (Box 93, Folder 1099)
  - Ford Foundation Statement to The Special Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations, H. Rowan Gaither, Jr., House of Representatives, 83rd Congress, 1954 July 16 (Box 93, Folder 1100)
  - The Ford Foundation: A History Draft, Lloyd Garrison, Director, Foundation History Project, undated (Box 93, Folder 1101)
  - Pamphlet - Intercultural Publications, Inc., Established by the Ford Foundation, 1952 (Box 93, Folder 1102)
  - Brochure - Announcement of a Program of Grants to Colleges and Universities to Help Support the Released Time of Faculty for Broadcasts Over Television Stations Having Educational Licenses, 1955 December (Box 93, Folder 1103)
  - Announcement of Interdisciplinary Research and Study Program, The Ford Foundation, Behavioral Sciences Division, undated (Box 93, Folder 1104)
  - Documento Evaluativo de los Directores participantes del Programa de Formación, Lilliam Hidalgo Collazos, 1995 December (Box 93, Folder 1105)
    Tarea, Asociación de Publicaciones Educativas, Area de Gestion Educativa, Proyecto: "Procesos de Gestión y Descentralización Educativa en Espacios Locales"
  - Organization, Development and Management of the Bangladesh Rice Research Institute and Its Programs, Wayne H. Freeman, Donald J. Minehart, and M. B. Russell, The Ford Foundation and The International Rice Research Institute, Dacca, 1974 February (Box 93, Folder 1106)
  - Demographic Crisis: The Impact of the Bangladesh Civil War (1971) on Births and Deaths in a Rural Area of Bangladesh, George T. Curlin, Lincoln T. Chen, Sayed Babur Hussain, The Ford Foundation, Dacca, 1975 April (Box 93, Folder 1107)
  - Photo Album - Ford Foundation Vietnam, 2000-2009 (Box 114, Folder 1326)
    Một Số Hình Anh Hoạt Dộng Của Các Lớp, Dvsk Ca Kich Hue Dvsk Tuong Va Mua Hat Cung Dinh Hue Nhac Cong Tryuen Tong Hue, Do Quy Ford Foundation Tai Tro
  - Job 92-22: Financing an Effective United Nations for the Future - Lists File, 1993-1994 (Box 93, Folder 1108)
  - Job 92-22: Financing an Effective UN - Press & Copies of Book & Background Papers, 1992-1993 (Box 93, Folder 1109-1110, Box 94, Folder 1111)
  - Job 92-22: Financing an Effective UN (Database - Lists), 1993 April 2 (Box 94, Folder 1112-1113)
  - Job 93-16: The Status of Women's Studies: A Program on Education and Culture, 1992-1994 (Box 94, Folder 1114)
  - Minorities in Business: Ford Foundation Assistance, 1965-1975 (2 copies), 1976 June (Box 94, Folder 1115)
  - Studying the Presidency: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Hugh Heclo (2 copies), 1977 August (Box 94, Folder 1116)
  - Grass-Roots Environmentalists: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to Municipal Conservation Commissions (2 copies), 1977 August (Box 94, Folder 1117)
  - Feminism in the Mid-1970s: The Non-Establishment, The Establishment, and the Future: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Maren Lockwood Carden (2 copies), 1977 (Box 94, Folder 1118)
  - Women in Blue-Collar Jobs: A Ford Foundation Conference Report (2 copies), 1976 (Box 94, Folder 1119)
  - A Work Experiment: Six Americans in a Swedish Plant (2 copies), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1120)
  - Relevance of Demographic Transition Theory for Developing Countries, Michael S. Teitelbaum, 1975 (Box 95, Folder 1121)
    Reprinted from Science, 2 May 1975, Volume 188, pp. 420-425
  - The Ford Foundation and African Studies, Francis X. Sutton and David R. Smock (2 copies), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1122)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from the summer/fall, 1976, edition of Issue: A Quarterly Journal of Opinion
  - Funding for International Education, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Francis X. Sutton (2 copies), 1975 February (Box 95, Folder 1123)
    Adapted from remarks given at a conference on international education at Columbia University, February 13 and 14, 1975
  - Women at Mexico: Beyond Family Planning Acceptors, Adrienne Germain (2 copies), 1975 (Box 95, Folder 1124)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Family Planning Perspectives, Vol. 7, No. 5
  - International Programs of the Ford Foundation (French and Spanish; 6 copies and 3 editions), 1973 July (Box 95, Folder 1125)
  - Matters of Choice: A Ford Foundation Report on Alternative Schools, K. C. Cole Janssen (2 copies), 1974 September (Box 95, Folder 1126)
  - Ford Foundation Agricultural Programs: Observations and Issues, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Lowell S. Hardin (2 copies), 1974 April-May (Box 95, Folder 1127)
    Adapted from presentations at Ford Foundation Agricultural Seminars: Ibadan, April 29-May 3, 1974; Chiengmai, Thailand, May 8-10, 1974
  - Urban Studies and the University - The Ford Foundation Experience, A Ford Foundation Reprint, William C. Pendleton (2 copies), 1974 (Box 95, Folder 1128)
    Adapted from an address delivered at the New Orleans Regional Conference of the Office of Urban Affairs, American Council on Education, April 5, 1974
  - School Finance: The Rising Tide of Reform, A Ford Foundation Reprint, James A. Kelly (2 copies), 1978 (Box 95, Folder 1129)
    Adapted from remarks at the 1978 Institute for Chief State School Officers on August 1, at South Padre Island, Texas
  - Title IX: Now What?, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Policy Issues in Education, Terry Tinson Saario (2 copies), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1130)
    A list of Ford Foundation grants in assistance for women's rights begins on page 14.
  - Citizen, Schooling, and Education, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Harold Howe II (3 copies), 1977 (Box 95, Folder 1131)
    Remarks were adapted from an address before the Citizens Committee on Public Education, Philadelphia, April 20, 1977
  - Mobilizing University Resources Against Hunger and Malnutrition, A Ford Foundation Reprint, David E. Bell (2 copies), 1977 May (Box 95, Folder 1132)
    Adapted from remarks made at a conference on "The University and Title VII," University of Montana, May 1977
  - Deciding About Grants, A Ford Foundation Reprint from The Grantsmanship Center News, Willard J. Hertz (2 copies), 1977 (Box 95, Folder 1133)
    Reprinted from the January-March 1977 edition of The Grantsmanship Center News
  - Housing in a Just Society, A Ford Foundation Reprint, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1977 March (Box 95, Folder 1134)
    Remarks prepared for the annual dinner of the Connecticut Housing Investment Fund (CHIF) on March 2, 1977 at which the Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company received CHIF's second annual award for corporate responsibility in housing. A note on Ford Foundation support for open housing begins on page 10.
  - Improving Schools: Looking Back to See Ahead, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Edward J. Meade, Jr. (2 copies), 1973 January (Box 95, Folder 1135)
    Address delivered by the Council of State Science Supervisors, Las Vegas, Nevada, January 29, 1973
  - Television and Children: Priorities for Research, Report of a Conference at Reston, Virginia (2 copies), 1975 November 5-7 (Box 95, Folder 1136)
  - Investment in Education in Developing Nations: Policy Responses When Private and Social Signals Conflict, A Ford Foundation Reprint from World Development, Edgar O. Edwards (2 copies), 1975 (Box 95, Folder 1137)
    Article reprinted from World Development, Vol. 3, No. 1, January 1975
  - The States and Private Foundations, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Howard R. Dressner (2 copies), 1975 April (Box 95, Folder 1138)
    Adapted from an address delivered at a meeting of the Special Committee on Charitable Trusts and Solicitations of the National Association of Attorneys General, Miami, April 16, 1975
  - Redirections in Educational Development, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Teachers College Record, F. Champion Ward (2 copies), 1975 May (Box 95, Folder 1139)
    Reprinted from Teachers College Record, Vol. 76, No. 4, May 1975
  - University/City Relations Revisited, A Ford Foundation Reprint, William C. Pendleton (2 copies), 1975 (Box 95, Folder 1140)
    Adapted from addresses delivered at Portland State University, February 25, 1975 and the Fourth Colorado Regional Urban Conference
  - Ford Foundation Assistance to Native Americans (2 copies), 1977 December (Box 95, Folder 1141)
  - The Very Small College: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Joseph A. Kershaw (2 copies), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1142)
  - Measuring Social Innovation, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Mitchell Sviridoff (2 copies), 1977 July (Box 95, Folder 1143)
    Adapted from remarks given at the Governor's Manpower and Supported Work Conference, Madison, Wisconsin, July 7, 1977; A note on other Ford Foundation activities with implications for social policy begins on page 11.
  - Contraceptive Development for Developing Countries: Unmet Needs, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Contraceptives of the Future, G. W. Perkin, G. W. Duncan, R. T. Mahoney, and R. H. Smith (2 copies), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1144)
  - American Foundations and Public Management in Developing Countries, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Francis X. Sutton (2 copies), 1977 March (Box 95, Folder 1145)
    Reprinted from "Education and Training for Public Sector Management in the Developing Countries," Rockefeller Foundation, March 1977, and also appears in Studies in Comparative International Development, Vol. 12, No. 2, Transaction, Inc., Rutgers University, New Brunswick
  - Theater Reawakening: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to American Drama and Supplement to Theater Reawakening: Individual Awards (2 copies), 1977 April (Box 95, Folder 1146)
  - On Training Teachers: Trust in the Classroom, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Edward J. Meade, Jr. (2 copies), 1975 February (Box 96, Folder 1147)
    Adapted from a speech at the annual meeting of the American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education in Chicago on February 27, 1975